Inventory of the Robert Blackwell Papers 1797-1880
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Robert Blackwell Papers, 1797-1880.
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 39.2 B56
75 items.
Correspondence of Robert Blackwell and business records of the Blackwell family mill, tanyard, store and farm, Lunenburg County, Virginia, dated 1797-1880.
Blackwell Family,; Robert Blackwell,; Upton Hardy.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 75 items, January 1928.
Scope and Content Information
Letters, 1835-1859, written to Robert Blackwell "Brickland," Lochleven, Lunenburg County, Virginia from relatives in Tennessee and Texas; and business records of the Blackwell family mill, tanyard, store and farm. Includes papers relating to the lawsuit of Blackwell and Featherston v. Hawthorne; and a letter, 30 November 1847, from Upton E. Hardy to his guardian Robert Blackwell asking permission to leave because of his illness and discussing Benjamin Stoddert Ewell's advice to him.
Arrangement
Organization
This collection is organized into 4 Series. Series 1 contains letters; Series 2 contains legal papers; Series 3 contains accounts; and Series 4 contains other papers.
Arrangement
This collection is first arranged into series. Then, series 1 and 2 are arranged chronologically and series 3 is arranged alphabetically.
Index Terms
Family Names:
Blackwell family.
Persons:
Blackwell, Robert.; Ewell, Benjamin Stoddert.; Hardy, Upton E.
Subjects:
Millers--Virginia.; Leather industry and trade--Virginia.
Corporate Names:
Washington and Lee University -- History.
Geographical Names:
Lunenburg County (Va.)--History -- 19th century.
Contents List
  Series 1: Letters
- Letters, 1835-1859. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Benjamin E. Blackwell, Montgomery County, Tennessee, to Robert Blackwell, at Oak Grove Post Office, Lunenburg County, Virginia, 15 July 1835. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Jacob Shough, at Mount Israel, Albermarle County, Virginia, to Robert Blackwell, at Brickland, Lunenburg, County, Virginia, 6 August 1842. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Charles A. Tucker, at Warrenton, Warren County, Virginia, to Robin [i.e. Robert] Blackwell, ar Brickland, Lunenburg County, Virginia, 29 January 1846. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - D. Hardy, at Grenada, Yellowbusha [Yalobusha] County, Mississippi, to Robert Blackwell, at Lockleaven [Lochleven], Lunburg [Lunenburg County], Virginia, 12 April 1847. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - John C. Blackwell, at Lexington, to Robert Blackwell, at Lochleven P.O., Lunenburg County, Virginia, 1 June 1847. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Upton E. Hardy, at Washington College, [Lexington, Virginia], to Robert Blackwell, at Lochleven P.O., Lunenburg County, Virginia, 30 November 1847. (Box-folder 1:1)
    Commenting on Professor Benjamin S. Ewell
  - Benjamin E. Blackwell, Giles County, Tennessee, to Robert Blackwell, at Lochleven P.O., Lunenburg County, Virginia, 31 December 1847. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - John C. Blackwell, to Robert Blackwell, at Lochleven, Lunenburg County, Virginia, 5 December 1848. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - William Dixon, Sussex County, Virginia, to Robert Blackwell, at Lochleven Post Office, Lunenburg County, Virginia, 9 March 1849. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Joh Lee, at Petersburg, to Robert Blackwell, at Lochleven, Lunenburg County, Virginia, 21 April 1849. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - John C. Blackwell, at the Institute, to Robert Blackwell, at Lochleven, Lunenburg County, Virginia, 26 May 1849. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Benjamin E. Blackwell, at Bonham, Texas, to Robert Blackwell, 1 June 1850. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Benjamin E. Blackwell, at Jefferson, Texas, to Robert Blackwell, at Lochleven Post Office, Lunenburg County, Virginia, 18 January 1851. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Benjamin Blackwell, at Bonham, Texas, to Robert Blackwell, at Lochleven Post Office, Lunenburg County, Virginia, 18 January 1851. (Box-folder 1:1)
    Enclosure: Order on Robert Blackwell for $150.
  - W. O. Goode [from the House of Representatives, Washington, D.C.], to Robert Blackwell, at Lochleven, Lunenburg County, Virginia, 23 February 1859. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - William B. Roberts, at Pulaski Post Office, Giles County, Tennessee, to Robert Blackwell, at Lochleven Post Office, Lunenburg County, Virginia, n.d. (Box-folder 1:1)
  Series 2: Legal Papers
- Legal Papers, 1869-1880. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Blackwell & Featherston v. P. W. Hawthorn. 1869-1871., 2 items. (Box-folder 1:1)
    Suit in Lunenburg County, Virginia.
  - Hawthorn (George H.) et al. v. L. A. M. Hawthorn et al. 1880., 2 items. (Box-folder 1:1)
    Suit in Brunswick County, Virginia.
  Series 3: Accounts
- Accounts, 1797-1859. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Blackwell (John) estate, 1841., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Blackwell (Mrs. Mary D.), 1843-1846., 2 items. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Blackwell (R.), 1843-1846., 6 items. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Blackwell (Robert), 1835-1854., 23 items. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Blackwell (Rober, Jr.) estate, 1829., 2 items. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Edmondson (Upton), 1800-1810., 4 items. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Parrish (Lucy and Robert) guardianship, 1797-1805., 15 items. (Box-folder 1:1)
  Series 4: Other Papers
- Other Papers, n.d. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Drafts of public addresses on George Washington by unknown persons, n.d., 3 items. (Box-folder 1:1)
    The name John Blackwell appears in different hand in the upper margin on one sheet.